Guide to the Lynn Langham collection, 1975-2017 MS 707
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Lynn Langham collection
1975-1981
2017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Langham, Lynn
MS 707
0.25 Linear Feet (1 box)
12.1 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0707aip_001 (12.1 GB)
2.46 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0707aip_002 (2.46 GB)
0.641 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0707aip_001 (0.641 GB)
This collection consists of digital images and hard copies of lyrics, news clippings, photographs, and other materials.
Biographical / Historical
Lynn Langham grew up in Texas and spent her teen years in Freeport, Texas. At an early age, she gravitated to music learning first the piano and then the guitar. When she began college at the University of Texas, she started playing clubs in Austin and moved on to playing in Houston, Dallas, and Denton.
While in Houston, she became a part of the music community at Anderson Fair Retail Restaurant. On a daily basis, songwriters shared their work and motivated and challenged each other to improve as writers, players, and performers. She appears on the 12" LP "Through the Dark Nightly," which featured players from the venue.
At the request of a friend, she spent time in New York. She played at the famed Bitter End and other clubs in the area. Before ultimately relocating to Los Angeles, she briefly returned to Houston to continue her career.
After a long break from the music business and performing, she began recording again in Los Angeles. Moving to Nashville in 1989, she received a recording contract with Capital Nashville and began writing songs for a publishing company, Hayes Street Music. Although the album deal eventually fell through, she continued working for Hayes Street. While the writing scene has changed in Nashville, she continues to write and tours with her partner Doug Gill.
Her work has been recorded by Wynona Judd, Trisha Yearwood, and Carolyn Hester. The song "Old Yellow Moon," which she co-wrote with Hank DeVito, is the title cut of the Grammy winning 2014 Americana Album of the Year by Emmylou Harris and Rodney Crowell.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of digital images, hard copies of lyrics, news clippings, photographs, business records, and other items chronicling Lynn Langhams 1970s to early 1980s career.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Lynn Langham in August 2017.
Related Materials
Please the Rice University KTRU Radio records, UA 011
Index Terms
Subjects
Music; Folk-rock music; Folk music; Folk music -- Texas -- Houston; Women
Subjects (Persons)
Langham, Lynn
- Series I: General files, 1975-1981
  - Business records, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fliers, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Folk City Gazette", ca. 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lyrics, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "The Music Connection", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - News clippings, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs (printed and digital images), 1975-1980s (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Scope and Contents
    Digital images include those of Lynn Langham, Shake Russell, Dana Cooper, John Vandiver, and Lucinda Williams. Contains the following: wrc08563, wrc08564, wrc08566, wrc08567, wrc08568, wrc08571, wrc08572, wrc08573, wrc08574.
  - Promotion, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Set lists, 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Williams, Lucinda, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II: Oral History, 2017
  - Video oral history, 2017-02-20
    These born digital video files consist of one master copy mov and one access copy located at scholarship.rice.edu.
- Series III: Audio
  - "Stones in the River" (CD), 2016 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Contents include: Master wav and access copy mp3 files. Songs include: "Stones in the River," "Dreams on the Wind," "The Key," "All of That Love," "On Any Given Day," "I'm Not Surprised," "Just a Little Pain," "Baby Have You Seen the Moon," "Trains," "I Have Been Waiting," "Heart of Hearts," "That's the Way the Teardrops Fall," "Only a Woman," "Old Yellow Moon"